Guide to the Papers of Mark Popovskii,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Research Materials
  - Subseries V.4: Notable Individuals
    - Kondratiuk, IUrii, 1980 - 1992 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      [Scientist, inventor of moon landing method]
    - Krein, Anna, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 5)
      [Psychotherapist]
    - Men', Aleksandr Background materials on A. Men', 1976 - 1991 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      [Russian Orthodox Priest]
    - Men', Aleksandr Writings and Correspondence by A. Men', 1979 - 1990 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Men', Aleksandr News Clipings on A. Men', 1985 - 1992 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Sakharov, Andrei, 1987 - 1991 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      [Soviet physicist, dissident]
    - Sctivel, Ruslan, 1995 - 1998 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      [Rare skin disease]
    - Vavilov, Nikolai Background materials on N. Vavilov, 1980 - 1988 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      [Genetics pioneer]
    - Vavilov, Nikolai; Strakhova, N. F. Typescript (by N. F. Strakhova, relative of Vavilov's wife), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Voino-Iasenetskii, Valentin Fedorovich Background Materials and notes on Luka Voino-Iasenetskii, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      [Archbishop and surgeon]
    - Voino-Iasenetskii, Valentin Fedorovich O Dukhe, Dushe I Tele, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Voino-Iasenetskii, Valentin Fedorovich Canonization, 1996 - 1999 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Whitney, Tom, 1991 - 1993 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      [Collector of Russian books]
    - Zvorykin, Vladimir, 1980 - 1982 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      [Inventor of TV]
  - Subseries V.5: Love and Sex in USSR
    - Besedy O Sekse v SSSR. 1981 - 1982 (Box 21, Folder 1 - 2)
    - Sex in the USSR - Anonimous Surveys, 1982 - 1983 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Sex Protiv Sotsialisma Research, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Sex in USSR - Clippings and notes, 1987 - 1990 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Subseries V.6: General Subjects
    Mostly news clippings
    - Science in Gorbachev's USSR, 1987 - 1991 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Science in Russian Press, 1992 - 1994 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Religion, [1990s] (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Russian Intelligentia, 1986 - 1988 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Censure in USSR, 1976 - 1990 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Soviet Writers and Perestroika, 1987 - 1999 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Series VI: Readers' Response
  Readers private and open letters, and polemics in émigré periodicals regarding Popovskii's articles. Arranged chronologically.
  - Korzhavin, Naum (Mandel') Pogovorim O Strannostiakh Liubvi, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Shvarts, Anatolii Polemics with Anatolii Shvarts, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Reznik, Semen Polemics with Semen Reznik, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Vaksberg, Arkadii Polemics with Arkadii Vaksberg, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Zudin, V. F. Polemics on death of N. I. Vavilov, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Primak, [...] Cherez Steklo, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Arzunian, Edvig Polemics on fifth waveof Russian Emigration, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Soloviev, Vladimir; Polenova, Lilia; Vasil'eva, Natalia; Gershovich, I. Zachem Pisateliu Sovest', 1992 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Kanevskii, Aron; Kovalev, Konstantin Rossiiskoe Pero V Amerikanskoi Chernil'nitse, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Lipkovich, Iakov; Maiskaia, Tamara; Albert, Sergei Pisateli V Mire Nechitaiushikh, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1984 - 1997 (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Series VII: About Popovskii
  Biographical information, personal documents, memorabilia, reviews of Popovskii's books and other materials regarding his life and works.
  - Biographies and autobiographies, 1984 - 1991 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Personal Documents, 1977 - 1994 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Humor, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Flyers for Lectures and Speeches, 1979 - 1991 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Birthday Selebrations, 1992, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Clippings - Russian, 1978 - 1999 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Clippings - English, 1968 - 1996 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Clippings - French, 1979 - 1980 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Clippings - Ukrainian, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Clippings - German, Dutch, 1979 - 1986 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Bakhmeteff Archive Popovskii Books and Papers, 1984 - 1997 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Oversized Memorabilia, 1979, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 1)
- Series VIII: Diaries
  - Diaries, 1971 - 1977 (Box 24)
  - Diaries, 1984 - Oct. 1989 (Box 25)
  - Diaries, Nov. 1989 - Apr. 1995 (Box 26)
  - Diaries, Apr. 1995 - Sep. 1999 (Box 27)
- Series IX: Writings by others
  Series contains literary works by miscellaneous Russian authors. Mostly typescripts, often inscribed to Popovskii by authors.
  - Bulanov Leonid Poems, 1997 - 2000 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Dizhur, Bella Poems, 1991 - 1999 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Druzhnikov, IUrii Novoe Russkoe Slovo Zhizn' I Zhitie Marka Popovskogo (article), 1992 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Genis, Aleksandr Desiat' Besed o Novoi Slovesnosti; Short Stories, 1996 - 2000 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Iampol'skii, Leonid Lekarstvo Ot Liubvi (short story), n.d. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - IArmolinets, Vadim Short Stories, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Kanevskii, Aron Poems, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Kapelian, Grigorii Inostrantsy o Rossii, Jersey City, NJ, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Katsenelinboigen, Aron J. Essays, 1988 - 1996 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Katso, Aleksandr Poems, 1990s (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Khazanov, Boris Short Stories, 2000 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Miller, Larisa Poems, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Naumov, Aleksandr (Naimark, Il'ia) Prichisleniie K Liky (Book Review on Voino-Iasenetskii); Poems, 1994 - 1997 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Obolenskii, Aleksandr Sviata Li Rus' (essay), 1989 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Paramonov, Boris Mif Dovlatova (essay), n.d. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Platova, Viktoria Bereg (short story), 1999 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Pustyl'nik, Semen Poems, 2000 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Siniavskii, Andrei Chtenie V Serdtsah (essay), 1985 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Sinkevich, Valentina Essays, 1991 - 1993 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Skolbin, IUrii Termidor - novella, [1980s], (79p. microfilm) (Box 28, Folder 19A)
  - Sokolov, Aleksandr Poems, 1996 - 1999 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Svirskii, Vladimir Essays, 1994 - 1995 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Vasilevskaia, Natal'ia Pervyi God (memoirs), 1989 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Zinov'eva, Liubov' Luna V Stakane (poems), 1980s - 1990s (Box 28, Folder 23)
- Series X: Printed Materials
  - Subseries X.1: Periodicals
    - Strana I Mir, 1984 Nos. 3 - 12; 1985, Nos. 1 - 12, Munich, Germany, 1984 - 1985 (Box 29)
      [Popovskii was an American Representative of Strana I Mir magazine, 1985 - 1990]
    - Strana I Mir, 1986 Nos. 1 - 12; 1987 Nos. 1 - 6, Munich, Germany, 1986 - 1987 (Box 30)
      [Strana I Mir becomes bimonthly since 1987]
    - Strana I Mir, 1988 Nos. 1 - 6; 1989 Nos. 1 - 6, Munich, Germany, 1988 - 1989 (Box 31)
    - Strana I Mir, 1990 Nos. 1 - 6; 1991 Nos. 1, 2, 4; 1992 Nos 1,2, Munich, Germany, 1990 - 1992 (Box 32)
    - Golos Zarubezh'ia, with Litsa I Maskiby M. Popovskii, Munich, Germany, Mar. 1998 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Vek XX I Mir, Moscow, Russia, Dec. 1988 - 1989 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Ural, with Russkie Muzhiki Rasskasyvaiutby M. Popovskii, 1992 Nos. 8, 10, 12, Ekaterinburg, Russia, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Osmyslenie Ameriki, with Nasha Emigratsiia V Treh Zerkalakhby Popovskii, St. Peterburg, Russia, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Subseries X.2: Miscellaneous Publications
    - Armalinskii, Mikhail Miscellaneous Publications, many inscribed to Popovskii by author, Minneapolis, MN, 1976 - 1997 (Box 33, Folder 5 - 6)
    - Eydinov, Iakov, et al Spetsial'nye Lechebnye Diety, incribed to Popovskii by Eydinov, Chicago, IL, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Patriarch - book about Alexii, patriarch of Russian Orthodox Church, incribed to Popovskii by Alexii IN 1998, Moscow, Russia, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Russian Orthodox Communities in New York State, Nyack, NY; Spring Valley, NY, 1960 - 1980 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Svodnyi Spisok Knig Podlezhashikh Iskliucheniiu Is Bibliotek I Knigotorgovoi Seti, Moscow, USSR, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 6)
- Series XI: Photographs
  - Subseries XI.1: Correspondence
    Photos removed from correspondence.
    - Vasilevskaia, Tatiana Vasil'evna; Popovskii, Konstantin and family; Khotmakher, Leiba Popovskii Family pictures - 1 of 2, Moscow - St. Petersburg, Russia, 1983 - 1998, (18 4x6 color prints, 4 4x5 color prints, 1 2x3 color prints, ) (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Bishko, Genia Popovskii family pictures - 2 of 2, Israel, 1997 - 1999, (27 4x6 color prints, 1 8x10 b&w print, 1 3x3 b&w print, ) (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Farber, IAkov; Hospital and church dedicated to Voino-IAsenetskii; Visit of Patriarch Aleksii II; Museum of the History of Medicine; Tambov, Russia, 1993 - 1998, (6 4x6 color prints, 4 4x5 color prints, 1 8x12 color print, ) (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Maksimova, Olga Maksimov Family Pictures, Montreal, Canada, 1986 - 1991, (6 4x6 color prints, 3 4x5 color prints, ) (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Romanov, Anatolii Graves of Russian Emigration, 1997, (7 4x6 color prints, 2 4x5 color prints, ) (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Voino-IAsenetskaia, Ol'ga Valentinovna; Voino-IAsenetskaia, Tat'iana Voino-IAsenetskaii family pictures, 1990s, (2 4x6 color prints, 8 4x5 color prints, ) (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Bezdetskaia, Tat'iana; Ciobanu, Vasile; Diczbalis, Sigizmund; Dizhur, Bella; Druzhnikov, IUrii; Efimov, Igor; Emel'ianov, Vasilii; Glasov, [...]; Golitsina, Nina; Gosteva, Alevtina; Ilovaiskaia-Alberti, [...]; Kazarnovskaia, Mina; Khoury, Lora; Kriukov, Vladimir; Lavrova-Karelina, Lidia; Levitan, Efim; Nakhalova, S. F.; Olsuf'ev, Nikolai; Pervova, IUlia; Rokhlin, Lev; Schedrinskii family; Shapoval family; Smith, Lidia; Sokolov, Valerii; Sorokina, Marina; Stoliarov, Isaac; Svirskii, Vladimir; Tsurupa, Aleksei; Zaitseva, Svetlana; Zelickman, Engelina Tolstoy Foundation; Miscellaneous Correspondents, 1919 - 2000, (28 4x6 color prints, 17 4x5 and smaller color prints, 1 5x7 color prints, 4x6 b&w prints, 20, 20 5x7 b&w prints) (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Subseries XI.1: Work Files
    Photos removed from work files.
    - Boldyrev, Sergei and Faia; Verbov, Mikhail; 1st and 2nd Waves of Russian Emigration., (5 8x10 b&w prints, 1 5x7 color print, mounted, 2 4x6 color print, ) (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Chalaia, Liudmila Photos for the Story of Chalaia, Liudmila - Russian girls, who came to New York and disappeared, n.d., (10 4x6 color print, 3 4x5 and smaller b&w prints, ) (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Cerni, Aleksandr Cerni, Aleksandr - related photographs (no photos of Cerni himself on file), n.d., (14 4x6 color print, 3 8x10 b&w prints, 2 5x7 b&w print, ) (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Men', Aleksandr Men', Aleksandr - life, funeral, grave, 1982 - 1997, (12 5x7 b&w print, 5 4x6 b&w print, 10 4x5 color print, 4 4x5 b&w print, ) (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Russian Children in America, 1990s, (10 4x6 color print, 2 4x5 color print, ) (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Mazurin, Boris; Iarkov, Ivan; Shershenev, Vasilii; Chertkov, Vladimir; Shokhor-Trotskii, Tolstovtsy, [1928 - 1976], (7 8x10 b&w prints, 14 5x7 b&w print, 1 5x7 b&w mounted print, 7 4x5 b&w negatives, ) (Box 34, Folder 13 - 15)
      [Each image counted once. Multiple duplicate prints in separate folder]
    - Voino-IAsenetskii, Valentin Feliksovich (Luka) Voino-Iasenetskii as student, surgeon, priest, his wife, co-workers, [1896 - 1953], (22 5x7 b&w print, 8 4x6 b&w print, 18 4x5 and smaller b&w prints, 1 6x8 b&w mounted print, ) (Box 34, Folder 16 - 18)
    - Voino-IAsenetskii, Valentin Feliksovich (Luka); Mikhailovskii, Ivan Voino-Iasenetskii Background Materials - photos of texts regarding works and death of Ivan Mikhailovskii, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - [Bezunov], Ivan; Frants, Yuri; Kachanov, Nikolai; Koltypin, Petr; Leibovich, Radik; Meerson-Aksenov, Mikhail; Morris, Stefan; Oksman, Natal'ia; Pitel'man, Gregory; Tameev, Varis; Vaizel', Sandra; Verbitskii, Georgii; Miscellaneous Photos from work files, (23 4x6 color print, 1 4x6 b&w print, 5 4x5 and smaller color print, 1 4x5 b&w print, ) (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Popovskii, Mark; Vladimov, Georgii Popovskii and Vladimov, New York, NY, Apr. 5, 1984 (Box 34, Folder 21)
- Series XII: Video
  Duplicates stored as reference copies in Box 37
  - Popovskii, Mark Interview, San Francisco, CA, Nov. 21, 1994, (1 VHS) (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Popovskii, Mark Russart Interview, San Francisco, CA, Nov. 28, 1994, (1 VHS) (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Kanevskii, Aron Liudi Sredi Liudei- 75th Birthday of Mark Popovskii, [New York, NY], Jul. 8, 1998, (1 VHS) (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Kanevskii, Aron Kapustnik- - 75th Birthday of Mark Popovskii, [New York, NY], Jul. 12, 1998, (1 VHS) (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Igor' Guberman S Utra Do Vechera, Jerusalem, Israel, n.d., (1 VHS, 2 VHS reference copy) (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Zdes' Nachinaetsia Rossiia; Miting Vulkanologov, n.p., Feb. - Mar. 1999, (1 VHS) (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Otets Aleksandr Men', n.p., n.d., (2 VHS) (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Za Drugi Svoia- Russian Orthodox Church During Soviet Atheism; Ya Vas Isbral- Archbishop Luka Voino-Iasenetskii, n.p., n.d., (1 VHS, 1 VHS reference copy) (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Unveiling Monument to Archbishop Luka, Tambov, Russia, Oct. 1994, (1 VHS) (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Congress of Russian Americans Kartiny Is Zhizni Congressa Russkih Americantsev, Nyack, NY, 1996, (1 VHS) (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Children on Another Shore, n.p., 1993 - 1996, (1 VHS) (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Nam - 85!- O Novom Russkom Slove, New York, NY, n.d., (1 VHS) (Box 35, Folder 12)
- Series XIII: Books by Popovskii
  - Kogda Vrach Mechtaet, Moscow: Trudreservisdat, 1957 (Box 36)
  - Put' K Serdtsu, Moscow: Isdatel'stvo Ministerstva Oborony SSSR, 1960 (Box 36)
  - Vtoroe Sotvorenie Mira, Moscow: Molodaia Gvardiia, 1960 (Box 36)
  - Tselitel'naia Stal', Moscow: Znanie, 1962 (Box 36)
  - Razorvannaia Pautina, Moscow: Sovetskaia Rossiia, 1963 (Box 36)
  - Po Sledam Otstupaiushchikh, Moscow: Molodaia Gvardiia, 1963 (Box 36)
  - Kormil'tsy Planety, Moscow: Znanie, 1963 (Box 36)
  - Sud'ba Doktora Havkina, Moscow: Isdatel'stvo Vostochnoi Literatury, 1963 (Box 36)
  - The Story of Dr. Haffkine, Moscow: Progress Publishers, [1965] (Box 36)
  - Piat' Dnei Odnoi Zhizni, Moscow: Detskaia Literatura, 1965 (Box 36)
  - Tysiacha Dnei Akademika Vavilova, Kazakhstan: Prostor, 1966 (Box 36)
  - Dorozhe Zolota, Moscow: Detskaia Literatura, 1966 (Box 36)
  - K. I. Skriabin (Razorvannaia Pautina), Bulgarian, Bolgaria: Zemizdat, 1967 (Box 36)
  - Nado Speshit', Moscow: Detskaia Literatura, 1968 (Box 36)
  - Nad Kartoi Chelovecheskih Stradanii, Moscow: Detskaia Literatura, 1971 (Box 36)
  - Liudi Sredi Liudei, Moscow: Detskaia Literatura, 1972 (Box 36)
  - Panatseia - Doch' Esculapa, Moscow: Detskaia Literatura, 1973 (Box 36)
  - N. I. Vavilov und die Biologische Discussion in der UdSSR (Delo Vavilova), German, Berlin, 1977 (Box 36)
  - Upravliaemaia Nauka, London: Overseas Publication Interchange, 1978 (Box 36)
  - Manipulated Science (Upravliaemaia Nauka), English, New York: Doubleday & Co., 1979 (Box 36)
  - Zhizn' I Zhitie Voino-Iasenetskogo, Arkhiepiskopa I Khirurga, Paris: YMCA-Press, 1979 (Box 36)
  - Russkie Muzhiki Rasskazyvaiut...: Posledovateli L. N. Tolstogo v Sovetskom Soiuze, London: Overseas Publication Interchange, 1983 (Box 36)
  - The Vavilov Affair (foreword by Andrei Sakharov), Hamden, CT: Shoe String Press, 1984 (Box 36)
  - Na Drugoi Storone Planety, Vol. 3, Philadelphia: Poberezh'e, 1996 (Box 37)
  - Zhizn' I Zhitie Voino-Iasenetskogo, Arkhiepiskopa I Khirurga, Tenafly, NJ: Hermitage Publishers, 1999 (Box 37)
- Series XIV: Scrapbooks
  Oversized Scrapbooks contain glued newspaper clippings of articles by/about Popovskii in miscellaneous émigré and Russian newspapers.
  - 1978 - 1990 (Box 40)
  - 1990 - 1994 (Box 41)
  - 1994 - 1997 (Box 42)
  - 1990-91, 1997-1999 (Box 43)
- Series XV: Audio
  Series consists of over 300 audio cassette tapes, primarily of interviews conducted by Popovskii. Also included are recording of lectures, radio broadcasts, and events
  - […], Svetlana (retired NYU teacher) (Box 44, Folder 44-10)
  - Aleinikov, Aleksandr (Box 44, Folder 44-1)
    [Same tape as Kovchegov, Vladislav]
  - Antipov, Evgenii (Box 44, Folder 44-3)
    [Same tape as Aron, Leon]
  - Aron, Leon (Box 44, Folder 44-2, 44-3)
  - Bakhtin, Vladimir (Box 44, Folder 44-4)
  - Belen'kii, Solomon (Box 44, Folder 44-5)
  - Belousov, Igor (Box 44, Folder 44-6)
  - Bentsianov, Eduard (Box 44, Folder 44-7)
    [same tape as Iampol'skii, Leonid]
  - Berkovich, Evgeniia (Box 44, Folder 44-8)
  - Bliakharov, Arkadii (Box 44, Folder 44-9)
    [same tape as Haisina, Raia]
  - Bliumenfel'd,, L. (Box 44, Folder 44-10)
    [same tape as […], Svetlana]
  - Bliumkin, Semen (Box 44, Folder 44-11)
  - Bobrinskii, N.A. (Box 44, Folder 44-14)
    [and his wife, Timasheva]
  - Boltnev, Zhorzh (Box 44, Folder 44-12, 44-13)
    [same tape as Gluzberg, Vadim]
  - Borodinskaia, Alla (Box 44, Folder 44-15, 44-15A)
  - Borovskii, Anatolii (Box 44, Folder 44-16)
  - Broier, Shloma (Box 44, Folder 44-17)
  - Buchin, Leonid (Box 44, Folder 44-18, 44-19)
    [Friends of Evsei Bykhovskii]
  - Buchina, Anna (Box 44, Folder 44-18, 44-19)
  - Budzulovich, Petr (Box 44, Folder 44-20, 44-20A, 48-21)
    [Congress of Russian Americans. Same tape as Tolstaia, Ol'ga (48-21)]
  - Bukrinskii, Mikhail (Box 44, Folder 44-21, 44-22)
    [same tape as Tarlovskaia, Lilia]
  - Burova, Nina (Box 44, Folder 44-23)
  - Buzikova, Svetlana (Box 44, Folder 44-24, 44-25)
    [same tape as Kartsev, […]]
  - Bykhovskii, Valerii (Box 44, Folder 44-26)
  - Bykova, Rozaliia (Box 44, Folder 44-27, 45-27)
    [same tape as Il'in, Aleksandr]
  - Chalova, Liudmila (Box 44, Folder 44-28, 44-29)
    [same tape as Moldavan, Vadim]
  - Cherkes, Igor (Box 44, Folder 44-30)
  - Cherni, Aleksandr (Box 44, Folder 44-31, 44-32, 44-33)
  - Cherniakhovskaia, Larisa (Box 44, Folder 44-34)
  - Cherniakhovskii, Mikhail (Box 44, Folder 44-34)
  - Cherniakhovskii, Mitchel (Box 44, Folder 44-34)
  - Chkheidze, Petr (Box 44, Folder 44-35, 44-36)
    [Georgia Representative at UN]
  - Chlenov, Mikhail (Box 44, Folder 44-37, 44-38)
    [same tape as Voskoboinikova, Evgeniia]
  - Daianaev, Lev (Box 44, Folder 44-39, 47-49)
    [same tapes as Khutoretskii, Efim, Sheveleva, Anna (47-49)]
  - Dantsig, Victor (Box 44, Folder 44-40)
    [same tape: beginning of lecture on Samisdat, N. Struve Arkhipelag GULAG; Novella Matveeva Devushka iz Kharchevni]
  - Dashevskii, Aleksandr (Box 44, Folder 44-41)
    [same tape as Moliver, Vladimir]
  - Denisevich, Tamara (Box 44, Folder 44-42)
  - Dikii, Elvart (Box 44, Folder 44-43)
  - Dil'man, Vladimir (Box 44, Folder 44-44)
  - Dremliuga, Vladimir (Box 44, Folder 44-45)
  - Edashkin, Robert (Box 44, Folder 44-46)
  - Enikolopov, I. (Box 44, Folder 44-57)
  - Fainberg, Israil' (Box 44, Folder 44-47)
  - Fei, V. (Box 44, Folder 44-48)
  - Feigin, Grigorii (Box 44, Folder 44-49, 44-50, 44-51, 44-52, 46-9)
    [same tape as Kvitash, Vadim (46-9)]
  - Fel'd, Dima (about) (Box 44, Folder 44-53)
    [conversations with Klim and Pavel]
  - Flam, Liudmila (Box 44, Folder 44-54)
  - Frants, Iurii (Box 44, Folder 44-55. 44-56, 44-57)
    [same tape as Enikolopov, I.I.]
  - Frolova, Lena (Box 44, Folder 44-58, 44-59, 44-60)
  - Gluzberg, Vadim (Box 44, Folder 44-13)
  - Haisina, Raia (Box 44, Folder 44-9)
  - Iaglom, Miriam (Box 44, Folder 44-7A, 44-7B)
  - Iampol'skii, Leonid (Box 44, Folder 44-7)
  - Kartsev, […] (Box 44, Folder 44-24)
  - Khutoretskii, Efim (Box 44, Folder 44-39)
  - Kovchegov, Vladislav (Box 44, Folder 44-1)
  - Tarlovskaia, Lilia (Box 44, Folder 44-22)
  - Timasheva, T.N. (Box 44, Folder 44-14)
  - Voskoboinikova, Evgeniia (Box 44, Folder 44-38)
  - Frumin, Boris (Box 45, Folder 45-1)
  - Fuks, Mikhail (Box 45, Folder 45-2)
  - Gabai, Genrikh (Box 45, Folder 45-3)
  - Gatker, Kim' (Box 45, Folder 45-4)
  - Genchikmakher, Marina (Box 45, Folder 45-5)
  - Gendler, Iurii (Box 45, Folder 45-6)
  - Gershman, Morris (Box 45, Folder 45-7)
  - Geskin, Liia (Box 45, Folder 45-8)
  - Gilbershtadt, Anna (Box 45, Folder 45-9)
  - Ginsburg, Evgenii (Box 45, Folder 45-10)
  - Ginsburg, Mark (Box 45, Folder 45-11)
  - Ginsburg, Valentina (Box 45, Folder 45-12, 45-12A)
  - Glupak, Sergei (Box 45, Folder 45-13, 47-23)
    [same tape as Prikhno, Igor]
  - Gluzkater, Sofiia (Box 45, Folder 45-14)
  - Gofman, Boris (Box 45, Folder 45-15)
  - Gol'den, Irvin (Box 45, Folder 45-16)
  - Golitsyn, Vladimir (Box 45, Folder 45-17)
  - Gorbenko, Dmitrii (Box 45, Folder 45-18)
  - Gordon, Asia (Box 45, Folder 45-19)
    [Association of Russian-Speaking Parents]
  - Gorod[ishcheva], Viktoria (Box 45, Folder 45-20)
    [same tape as Klimenko, Viktor]
  - Klimenko, Viktor (Box 45, Folder 45-20, 45-51)
    [same tape as Gorod[ishcheva], Viktoria]
  - Grigor'ev, Dmitrii (Box 45, Folder 45-21, 45-22)
  - Gurevich, Dmitrii (Box 45, Folder 45-23)
  - Gurevich, Nadezhda (Box 45, Folder 45-24, 45-25)
  - Gurevich, Vladimir (Box 45, Folder 45-26)
  - Il'in, Aleksandr (Box 45, Folder 45-27)
    [same tape as Bykova, Rozalia]
  - Kachanov, Nikolai (Box 45, Folder 45-28, 45-29)
  - Kalinskii, Feliks (Box 45, Folder 45-30)
    [same tape as Smelianskii, […]]
  - Smelianskii, […] (Box 45, Folder 45-30)
    [same tape as Kalinskii, Feliks]
  - Kanevskii, Anatolii (Box 45, Folder 45-31, 45-32)
  - Karabach, Maksim (Box 45, Folder 45-33, 45-34)
  - Karabach, Marina (Box 45, Folder 45-35, 45-36, 45-37)
    [mother of Karabach, Maksim. same tape as Dashkova, Raia, mother of Lera]
  - Dashkova, Raia (Box 45, Folder 45-35)
  - Karmazina, Evgeniia (Box 45, Folder 45-38)
  - Kasinec, Edward (Box 45, Folder 45-39, 46-18)
    [same tapes as Kaialova, Ania (45-39), Magarshak, IUrii (46-18)]
  - Kaialova, Ania (Box 45, Folder 45-39)
    [same tape as Kasinec, Edward]
  - Kastil'o, Galina (Box 45, Folder 45-40)
  - Kataev, Il'ia (Box 45, Folder 45-41)
    [son of Evgenii Petrov. Story about Pokrass, Dmitrii]
  - Katsenelinboigen, Aron (Box 45, Folder 45-42, 45-43, 45-44, 45-45)
  - Kazanskii, Boris (Box 45, Folder 45-46, 45-47)
  - Khanga, Elena (Box 45, Folder 45-48)
  - Kisin, Michael (Box 45, Folder 45-49, 45-50)
    [same tape as trip to Brooklyn to the Center of Psychological Help for Russian Emigrants, May 1991]
  - Klarkson, Natalia (Box 45, Folder 45-52)
  - Koliuzhskii, Boris (Box 45, Folder 45-53)
    [same tape as Krochek, Gennadii (editors of Vestnik)]
  - Krochek, Gennadii (Box 45, Folder 45-53, 47-20)
    [same tape as Koliuzhskii, Boris]
  - Kogan, Mark (Box 45, Folder 45-54)
  - Kolesnikova, Raisa (Box 45, Folder 45-55)
    [about Men', Aleksandr. Maybe more on 46-27]
  - Kondrashova, Natasha (Box 45, Folder 45-56)
  - Konstantinov, Andrei (Box 45, Folder 45-57)
  - Kotliar, Lina (Box 45, Folder 45-58)
    [same tape as Rudziak, […]]
  - Rudziak, […] (Box 45, Folder 45-58)
    [same tape as Kotliar, Lina]
  - Kozyreva, Natasha (Box 45, Folder 45-59, 45-60, 45-61)
    [Russkii Muzei, St. P.]
  - Alekseeva, Evelina (Box 46, Folder 46-15)
    [same tape as Loskutova, Tania]
  - Arzunian, Valia (Box 46, Folder 46-5, 46-12)
    [same tapes as: Kriukov, […] (46-5); Lifshits, Anna, Grinshtup, Grigorii and Elena (46-12)]
  - Arzunian, Ed. (Box 46, Folder 46-12)
    [same tape as Lifshits, Anna, Grinshtup, Grigorii and Elena]
  - Doroshevich, Vladimir (Box 46)
  - Fridman (or Friman), Margarita (Box 46, Folder 46-16, 48-46)
    [same tapes as Loskutova, Tania, Zarudnaia, Elena (48-46)]
  - Galina, Evgeniia (Box 46, Folder 46-55)
  - Ginsburg, Konstantin (Box 46, Folder 46-6)
    [same tape as Krichevskaia, Uilia (which may be over KG)]
  - Golubintsev, Anatolii (Box 46, Folder 46-26)
    [same tape as Maksimov, Sergei]
  - Grinshtup, Grigorii (Box 46, Folder 46-12)
    [same tape as Lifshits, Anna, Arzunian, Valia and Ed.]
  - Grinshtup, Elena (Box 46, Folder 46-12)